{"tossups": [{"question": "One character in this story is impressed that another exchanged twenty-threesword strokes with him before losing, as no one had ever lasted that long before.A woman in this story fails to commit suicide by stabbing her throat and throwingherself into a (+) pond, and her sword is used by another character for his suicide, astold through a medium. One character is arrested with seventeen arrows in his quiver, although a Buddhist (*) priest claims there were more than twenty. A rope and comb are found as the only evidence for a crime off the Yamashina stage road for which Tajomaru is arrested. For ten points, name this short story in which three different accounts are given for a murder in the title location written by Ryunosuke Akutagawa.", "answer": "In a Grove (or Yabu no Naka)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>In a Grove</u></b>", "acceptable": ["In a Grove"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Yabu no Naka"}, {"question": "One character in this work runs out of adjectives after \"retrogressive, remarkable,unpalatable\" but promises more when his Longer Companion Dictionary arrives.Another character in this play claims that her image took three leaves - one for eachheart she will break. That character is seduced by promises that her (+) face willappear on stamps. At the end of the first act, four women play the tires of a truck that breaks down and whose driver falls in water before taking pictures of the village; those pictures later appear in a (*) magazine from the capital. A teacher confusedly believes that a belle will marry him without demanding a bride price, but she marries the Baleof Ilujinle instead. For ten points, name this play in which Lakunle loses the hand of Sidi to Baroka written by Wole Soyinka.", "answer": "The Lion and the Jewel", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Lion and the Jewel</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Lion and the Jewel"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one work by this author, the narrator mentions giving away copies of Omar Khayyam in a monologue criticizing Christmas presents. Another title character of this writer ate a gipsy child before being hit by a car, resulting in a diamond broach for the on-looking baroness. In addition to (+) Reginald and Esme the hyena, he wrote of a woman for whom \"Romance at short notice was her specialty\". While on a Carpathian hunting trip, a fallen (*) limb traps two enemies, Georg Znaeym and Ulrich von Gradwitz, until wolves arrive. One character's sudden departure in one story is explained with a dog chase in India, although he had earlier been told that the returning hunting crew had been dead for three years. For ten points, name this author of the short stories The Interlopers and The Open Window.", "answer": "Saki or Hector Hugh Munro", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Saki or Hector Hugh <b><u>Munro</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Saki or Hector Hugh Munro"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poet wrote a poem that opened \"It was not dying: everybody died\" calledLosses. In another poem, he declared that the title figure \"look[s] back at the leopardlike the leopard\" but that \"the world goes by my cage and never sees me\". Thisauthor wrote a novel about the creative writing instructor (+) Mrs. Batterson andthe twelve-tone composer Gottfried Rosenbaum teaching at a women's college. This author of The Woman at the Washington Zoo wrote satirically of Benton in (*) Pictures from an Institution. In his most famous poem, he wrote of his \"wet fur\" freezing after falling from his \"mother's sleep\" to \"black flak and the nightmare fighters\" and stated that \"when I died they washed me out. . . with a hose\". For ten points, name this American poet of The Death of a Ball Turret Gunner.", "answer": "Randall Jarrell", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Randall Jarrell</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Randall Jarrell"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poem uses the image of \"TV's giant paperclip\" from its author's earlierpoem The Swing in describing his garden among \"the svelte/ stilettos of a frozenstillicide\". This poem's third section abbreviates Institute of Preparation for theHereafter as \"Iph\". Its second canto tells of a (+) geology field trip on which theauthor fell in love with his eventual wife, Sybil, and says \"She may not be a beauty, but she's cute\" before the icy lake death of his daughter, (*) Hazel. This poem's use of the word \"gradual\" arguably refers to Jakob Gradus, a would-be Zemblan assassin. The couplet of this poem's final line is completed by the first line, \"I was the shadow of the waxwing slain\". For ten points, name this 999-line John Shade poem commented on by Charles Kinbote in an eponymous novel by Vladimir Nabokov.", "answer": "Pale Fire", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Pale Fire</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Pale Fire"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this short story, the wife of the protagonist tells him to examine a goat so thather lover could escape. That character had left his post when he was told that theMessiah had come and that his parents had risen from the grave. The title characterof this story is matched up with (+) Elka, who has a bastard son and who has anotherson just seventeen weeks after their wedding. At the end, the title character leaves the town of Frampol to become a beggar. The protagonist's (*) rabbi tells him to leave his wife for her infidelity, but he remains loyal until her death. The protagonist is convinced by the Spirit of Evil to add urine to his dough. For ten points, name this story about a gullible title character written by Isaac Bashevis Singer.", "answer": "Gimpel the Fool                                                                             [BAH-   lay]                                                                                                                                                      ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gimpel the Fool</u></b> [BAH-   lay]", "acceptable": ["Gimpel the Fool"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of this novel briefly works for Nanantatee, who pays for everythingwith pearls, and he visits the Pension Orfila because his girlfriend Mona had beenobsessed with Strindberg. The narrator of this novel is forced to leave the apartmentof the (+) artist Kruger so that he would not die in front of a potential patron. Thenarrator is invited to move to Crimea with his lover, although declines for fear that he could not find work as a proofreader. The narrator claims that (*) \"Paris is a whore\" and declares in his opening monologue that \"I am fucking you, Tania, so that you'll stay fucked\". A Russian princess named Macha moves in with the narrator and Fillmore, the latter of whom abandons Ginette and returns to America. For ten points, name this autobiographical novel about expatriates written by Henry Miller.", "answer": "Tropic of Cancer                                                                                                                                                                                                           ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Tropic of Cancer</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Tropic of Cancer"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one work in this collection, three girls conspire to use geraniums, cloths, and\"heavenly labials\", to \"check\", \"abash\", and \"undo\" the title figure. Another, whichquestions the story of the ugly duckling, is Sonatina to Hans Christian. In additionto The Plot Against The Giant, this collection contains a work in which (+) elderswatch Susanna bathe in her garden and another which states that \"The houses are haunted/ By white night-gowns\". Another poem in this collection, centering on a funeral, declares (*) \"Let be be finale of seem\" and bids to \"Call the roller of big cigars\" to \"whip\" \"concupiscent curds\". For ten points, name this poetry collection containing Peter Quince at the Clavier, The Disillusionment of Ten O'Clock, and The Emperor of Ice Cream written by Wallace Stevens.", "answer": "Harmonium", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Harmonium</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Harmonium"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one scene in this novel, a dozen buzzards carry the body of Gideon Tomfrom a dredge belonging to the Model Land Company. One character in this novel isgiven the nickname Margaret Mead, but after saving Emily Barton from drowning, iscalled Hell's Angel. After finding (+) The Spiritist's Telegraph, one character elopeswith her boyfriend Louis Thanksgiving. Kiwi discovers his father working at a casino and rescues his stranded sister Osceola. This novel opens with the death of (*) Hilola Bigtree, who had been known for her Swimming with the Seths routine, and is narrated by her daughter Ava, who trains to be an alligator wrestler. For ten points, name this Karen Russell novel about a bankrupt Florida tourist park.", "answer": "Swamplandia!", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Swamplandia!</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Swamplandia!"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This novel features the fiery death and consummation of Sister Aidan. Muchof this novel is told through letters from Gabriel van Onselen to his aunt. Followinghis conviction for violating the (+) Immorality Act, Jan Fischer commits suicide.While sitting in the home of Robert Mansfield, Prem Bodasingh was shot in her face; earlier, Prem had sat in protest in the Municipal Reference Library as part of the (*) Defiance Campaign in Durban. This novel, which contains the section The Cleft Stick, chronicles anti-apartheid activism in the 1950s. For ten points, identify this novel by Alan Paton whose name refers to the reaction of foreign visitors observing South African politics.", "answer": "Ah, But Your Land is Beautiful", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ah, But Your Land is Beautiful</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ah, But Your Land is Beautiful"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poem states that \"there at the bottom the eyes of a girl drowned a thousandyears ago\" show \"glance of the aged mother\". The narrator of this poem discussesmaking plans \"with Phyllis, who had two dimples in her cheeks where sparrows cameto drink the light\". The middle of this poem evokes (+) historical events, describingtwo people making love during the 1937 siege of Madrid and noting \"the numbered steps of Lincoln as he left/ for the theater\" and (*) \"Madero's gaze/ that no one returned: why are they killing me?\" This poem's last six lines repeat its first six, which mention \"a crystal willow, a poplar of water\" and \"a course of a river that turns, moves on/ doubles back, and comes full circle\". For ten points, name this 584-line poem based on the Aztec calendar written by Octavio Paz.", "answer": "Sunstone (or Piedra de Sol)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Sunstone</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sunstone"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Piedra de Sol"}, {"question": "The narrator of this novel learns of sadism by watching a young girl telling herfriend to spit on a photo of her dead father. Two characters in this novel use \"do acattleya\" as a euphemism for sex. The protagonist, a friend of the Prince of Wales,learns that his girlfriend had a sexual liaison while he dined with (+) Princesse desLaumes, and he originally learns of her infidelity by reading through the envelope in a letter she wrote to Forcheville. The narrator, who meets (*) Gilberte on the Champs-E \u0301lys \u0301ees, walks paths named for M \u0301es \u0301eglise and Guermantes in Combray. The protagonist is obsessed with a sonata by Vinteuil and attends the Verdurin's with Odette de Crecy. For ten points, name this first volume in Marcel Proust's In Search of Lost Time.", "answer": "Swann's Way (or Du C\u00c2\u02c6ot \u0301e de chez Swann, prompt on \"In Search of Lost Time\" or \"Remembrance of Things Past\" or \"A` la recherche du temps perdu\")", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Swann's Way</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Swann's Way"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Du C\u00c2\u02c6ot \u0301e de chez Swann, prompt on \"In Search of Lost Time\" or \"Remembrance of Things Past\" or \"A` la recherche du temps perdu\""}, {"question": "A psychologist in this work uses the spokes of a spinning wheel and the flight of abullet to verify the threshold of diluted presentation. The protagonist of this novellafinds a group of foreigners dumb because when he tries to indicate time by pointingto the sun, they think he is signaling thunder. The protagonist uses (+) camphor hefound hermetically sealed in a museum to burn his path behind him as he escaped from the Palace of Green Porcelain to a bronze chamber near a (*) white marble sphinx. This story, told primarily as a monologue to a group of journalist dinner guests, includes a forest fire that killed the protagonist's companion Weena, a member of the Eloi, while he ran from the Morlocks. For ten points, name this novella by H. G. Wells in which the protagonist visits 802,701 A.D.", "answer": "The Time Machine", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Time Machine</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Time Machine"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this play says that Indians \"like to talk to salesmen\". Anothercharacter in this play becomes an accomplice in a crime \"because [he] listened\", whilehis partner forms an (+) alibi by going to the Como Inn. Characters in this play usethe \"Kenilworth\" trick to avoid talking to James Lingk. One character in this play cannot afford a one-hundred dollar bribe, so he takes something off the (*) B list, as his two bosses would not give him anything better. A crime in this play is investigated by Baylen, although Williamson solves it when Levene caught him in a lie. The salesmen Dave Moss and Ricky Roma work for Mitch and Murray in, for ten points, which play about Chicago real estate agents by David Mamet?", "answer": "Glengarry Glen Ross", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Glengarry Glen Ross</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Glengarry Glen Ross"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A Samuel Taylor Coleridge poem notes that this river washes a city in whichhe \"counted two and seventy stenches\" and asked \"what power.../shall henceforthwash\" this river. Byron wrote \"Nor could on earth a spot be found/ To nature andto me so dear/ Could thy dear eyes.../Still sweeten\" the banks of this river as thenarrator travels it in the third canto of (+) Childe Harold's Pilgrimage. Anotherpoem about this river begins by stating \"I do not know what it should mean/ that I am so sad\" and mentions a (*) sailor who is looking up too high to see the rock reefs. That poem mentions a loveliest maiden using a golden comb on her golden hair on whose singing is blamed the destruction of a boat. For ten points, name this river that is the setting of Heinrich Heine's poem The Lorelei and which runs through Cologne.", "answer": "Rhine", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Rhine</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Rhine"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel comes up with an elaborate comeback to herboyfriend's assertion that a poem is a \"piece of dust\", and later tells him she has adate with Peter the Hermit and Walter the Penniless. The protagonist of this novelpetitions her (+) college dean to audit Mr. Manzi's chemistry class. The protagonistturns down a job as a waitress at a sanatorium in order to go to New York City, and later breaks her leg skiing while at the sanatorium visiting (*) Buddy Willard. She is sponsored at a hospital by the wealthy novelist, who had given her a scholarship before she interned at Ladies's Day Magazine, named Philomena Guinea. While in the hospital, she receives shock therapy under Doctor Nolan. For ten points, name this novel about the suicidal Esther Greenwood written by Sylvia Plath.", "answer": "The Bel l Jar", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Bel l Jar</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Bel l Jar"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this work repeatedly says \"Ftt\". Another character wraps a dog'stail in red kleenex to prevent it from being shot by hunters. Early in this book, thenarrator protects his boat from Hurricane Donna. The narrator travels to (+) NewOrleans to hear the Cheerleaders jeer outside a newly-desegregated school, and earlier fails to cross the border to Canada due to missing rabies vaccination documentation. That character celebrates Thanksgiving in Texas while his companion is being treated for prostatitis. Earlier, he is mocked by (*) Minnesotans for getting lost on his way to Sauk Centre, the birthplace of his friend Sinclair Lewis, while driving a truck called Rocinante. For ten points, name this book subtitled In Search of America about a journey with a dog written by John Steinbeck.", "answer": "Travels with Charley                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Travels with Charley</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Travels with Charley"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One man in this work is sacrificing his house for the construction of a fire lane,but he dies when it collapses early. Another figure in this work, while being treatedfor a weeks-old broken leg, is found to have spot hemorrhages. The Jesuit priest (+)Father Kleinsorge finds pumpkins roasted on the vine and a group of twenty soldiers with their eyes melted out. A Molotov flower basket or fine magnesium powder are theorized as the medium of an (*) attack, whose refugees gather in Asano Park to be cared for by Mr. Tanimoto. This work is divided into sections including The Details Are Being Investigated and The Noiseless Flash and begins \"at exactly fifteen minutes past eight in the morning on August 6, 1945\". For ten points, name this work of journalism by John Hersey profiling six survivors of the first atom bomb attack.", "answer": "Hiroshima                                                                                                                                                                                      ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Hiroshima</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Hiroshima"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One resident of this city is helped by the magician Persky to meet Emma Bovary.Another resident of this city hires Kelly to create a traffic jam so that his son canget engaged. A poem addressed to this home of professor (+) Kugelmass commands\"let black blood flow into your blood\", begins \"At first I was bewildered by your beauty\", and was written by L \u0301eopold Senghor. One resident of this city was forgiven for stealing an umbrella in a (*) cigar store and ignored while confessing to throwing a rock through a window, but was arrested for vagrancy while listening to a church organ. This home city of Soapy also saw Jim ironically give Della hair brushes. For ten points, name this city in which The Cop and the Anthem and The Gift of the Magi were set as part of O. Henry's collection The Four Million.", "answer": "New York, New York", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>New York, New York</u></b>", "acceptable": ["New York, New York"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The title character of one of this man's poems is described as \"Too poor to shinein courts, too proud to beg\" as he \"Sits musing o'er his scars, and wooden leg\" and hewas left only \"famine and a name\". Another poem by this author declares that \"Bymidnight moons\" (+) \"The hunter still the deer pursues\", as images called \"fancies ofa ruder race\" depict \"Activity, that knows no rest\". That poem questions the notion of death as \"soul's eternal sleep\". Another work assures the title figure (*) \"No roving foot shall crush you here\" before admitting \"I grieve to see your future doom\". This poet of The American Soldier and The Indian Burying Ground wrote that \"From morning suns and evening dews\" \"The space between is but an hour/The frail duration of a flower\". For ten points, name this poet of The Wild Honey Suckle.", "answer": "Philip Freneau", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Philip <b><u>Freneau</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Philip Freneau"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this work is appalled when a friend tells her that her dress \"willbe heavier soon by the weight of a man.\" Another character in this play is told not toswear by his sword, but to eat it, and he had earlier ended a string of back-and-forth(+) insults saying \"I would my horse had the speed of your tongue\"; that man was called a \"the prince's jester: a very dull fool\" while disguised at a ball. A wedding is (*) canceled when the groom declares the bride's \"blush is guiltiness, not modesty\". The report of \"comprehend[ing] two auspicious persons\" is given by the constable Dogberry. A liaison between Margaret and Borachio causes a rift between Claudio and Hero. For ten points, name this play culminating in the marriage of Beatrice and Benedick written by William Shakespeare.", "answer": "Much Ado About Nothing", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Much Ado About Nothing</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Much Ado About Nothing"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A teenage girl in this novel is sent home from a barricade in a student protest dueto a heavy period. The protagonist of this novel travels to the United States to consultwith doctors on whether he is shrinking. An engagement ceremony was damperedwhen the pet dog was found with a (+) butcher's knife in his back. One woman, whoconsults with Rosicrucians and the Mora sisters, has her mother's disembodied head under the bad when she gives birth to the twins (*) Jaime and Nicolas. Alba is born of the affair between Blanca and Pedro Tercero Garcia. After nine years of not speaking following the poisoning death of her green-haired sister Rosa, the clairvoyant Clara marries the protagonist. For ten points, name this novel about the life of Esteban Trueba written by Isabel Allende.", "answer": "The House of the Spirits (or La Casa de los esp \u0301\u0131ritus)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The House of the Spirits</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The House of the Spirits"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or La Casa de los esp \u0301\u0131ritus"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this work kills a sheep with a rock after a failed sacrifice duringa night of drinking in college with Steve Garvey and Jud Hume. That protagonist ofthis work dates a woman who repeats that her mother died of breast cancer as heundressed her in the elevator. The disillusioned protagonist promises to look for (+)an advertising job to his pregnant fiancee, Betty. Earlier, he had gone on a \"field trip\" to meet an admirer for a tryst, and later is asked the point of it all by that woman's crippled husband. The title character, who was part of a love triangle with (*) Peter and Fay Doyle, reads letters by Desperate and Sick-of-it-all and works for the editor Shrike at the New York Post-Dispatch. For ten points, name this novella about an advice columnist written by Nathanael West.", "answer": "Miss Lonelyhearts", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Miss Lonelyhearts</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Miss Lonelyhearts"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one work, this character is called a \"madman/ who idly strolls through life\".This character brings a blind fiddler he met on the street to dinner at the Sign ofthe Golden Lion. In another work, this character enters chasing his future wife in agame of (+) cat-and-mouse. His affair with Katherina Cavalieri is avenged when heis refused tutorship of Princess Elizabeth. In one work, this man dies when his drink is (*) poisoned by a rival, while in another, he dies in the arms of his wife, Constanze. One of his works has a dance scene removed as ballet, while another work of this composer is criticized for \"too many notes\" by Joseph, the Emperor of Austria. For ten points, name this character of Alexander Pushkin and Peter Schaffer whose rivalry with Salieri was the subject of Amadeus.", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart                                                                                                                                                                                                     ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story by this author, the voice of the Sweeney's nurse is identified asshe read about the Yonghy-Bonghy-Bo. Another work by this author ends with theburning of the manor at Clear Haven, where one character had found his wife afterhis name was tarnished by a bandleader's wife. That character's brother worked as a(+) Taper on Island 93, and his father had lost his ship, the Topaze, while crossing the Nagansakit. Those characters, from a novel based in St Botolphs, were (*) Moses, Coverly, and Leander. Another protagonist of this author traveled across the county from pool to pool before finding his house empty and was named Neddy Merrill. For ten points, name this author who wrote stories The Enormous Radio and The Swimmer for The New Yorker and wrote the novel The Wapshot Chronicle.", "answer": "John Cheever", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "John <b><u>Cheever</u></b>", "acceptable": ["John Cheever"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One story in this collection is about a man leaving his home and ends with himand his partner pulling on opposite arms of their baby. Another story sees Dummy killhis wife and himself after a flood destroys his bass pond. In addition to (+) PopularMechanics and The Third Thing That Killed My Father Off, this collection contains a story about Burt stealing his ex-wife's ashtray on the day after Christmas called A Serious Talk. The final story concerns L. D. being kicked out by his wife Maxine and not being able to say its titular One More Thing. This collection's story (*) The Bath was adapted into its author's later work A Small, Good Thing. The title story of this collection sees Mel and Terri debate whether her abusive ex-husband had really loved her. For ten points, name this short story collection by Raymond Carver.", "answer": "What We Talk About When We Talk About Love", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>What We Talk About When We Talk About Love</u></b>", "acceptable": ["What We Talk About When We Talk About Love"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character claims indifference to \"the bearer of Flemish wheat or Englishcottons\". This character dreams of \"the yellow and blue awakening of singingphosphorous\" and sees in a sunrise \"long violet clots/ Resembling actors of veryancient dramas\". This character tells of (+) \"yelping redskins\" taking his companionsand \"nail[ing] them naked to colored stakes\" and of enduring \"droppings of noisy birds with yellow eyes\". This figure says \"I should have liked to show children those (*) sunfish\", but abruptly changes tone to declare \"Every moon is atrocious and every sun bitter\" and to express feeling \"swollen...with intoxicating torpor\" before imploring \"O let me go into the sea!\" and \"let my keel burst!\" For ten points, name this title vessel of an Arthur Rimbaud poem about its free floating.", "answer": "the drunken boat (or le Bateau ivre)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the drunken boat</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the drunken boat"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or le Bateau ivre"}, {"question": "While cutting wood, this character saw a man cut off his own finger, most likelyto avoid service. This character became the Emperor of a lunatic asylum in Cairo aftermeeting Begriffenfeldt at the Sphinx. This character was abandoned in (+) Moroccowhen he could not convince his friends to stir up an insurrection in Greece against Turkey. This man put his mother on the mill-house roof after telling her a story of being carried into a pit on the back of a (*) buck he had been hunting. He agreed to be given a tail, but did not let the Dovre King distort his eye. This man's soul was sought by a button molder. This son of Aase gave a pearl to the dancing girl Anitra, but had been refused a dance at a wedding with Solveig. For ten points, name this title character of a dramatic poem by Henrik Ibsen.", "answer": "Peer Gynt", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Peer Gynt</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Peer Gynt"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man's father states that \"Sire, I am the head, he but an arm of mine\" inappealing to the king to save his life. This man summarizes his principal dilemmaas \"One makes me sad, the other unworthy\". This character is told \"I admire yourcourage, but regret your youth/ Do not attempt this fateful trial\" by the man he (+)challenges to a duel, although that man later accepts and loses. In one play in which he appears, two noblemen disagree about the newly-named tutor to the Prince of (*) Castile. This man's love begs the king to make him fight Don Sanche, with the winner receiving her hand. This lover of Chim`ene earned his title for capturing two enemy kings during a naval invasion by the Moors. For ten points, name this Spanish national hero and title character of a Pierre Corneille play.", "answer": "El Cid (or Le Cid or Don Rodrigue, prompt on \"Rodrigo\")                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>El Cid</u></b>", "acceptable": ["El Cid"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Le Cid or Don Rodrigue, prompt on \"Rodrigo\""}, {"question": "The generosity of one character in this play is inspired by the opera Ernani.Another character in this play is ordered to slam a bag down on some ice pudding.This play opens with tales of a victory at (+) Slivnitza, but later acts revolve ongetting three regiments to Phillipopolis. Two characters' deception in this play is revealed by a picture in a coat pocket signed to a man who had explained the foolish (*) cavalry charge of her betrothed, her \"chocolate cream soldier\". The servant Nicola comes onto the maid Louka, who is pursued by the army officer Sergius Saranoff, who is engaged to Raina, who saves the life of Captain Bluntschli during a war between Bulgaria and the Servs. For ten points, name this play about the Petkoff family written by George Bernard Shaw.", "answer": "Arms and the Man                                                                                                                                                                                            ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Arms and the Man</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Arms and the Man"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this play is asked to lock up her Diana trophy from anintercollegiate archery contest, and is later caught in a lie about a gifted cashmererobe she bought in Memphis. That character in this play calls her nieces and nephews(+) \"no-neck monsters\" and says that their names sound like four dogs and a parrot; those children included Trixie, Dixie, and Polly. This play's second act features a long dialogue about \"mendacity\". One man reveals to his father that the diagnosis from the Ochsner clinic was cancer, not a (*) spastic colon, after the father withheld a crutch for an ankle injury from jumping hurdles at night. That man feels the \"click\" from drinking after his wife lies about being pregnant to please Big Daddy. For ten points, name this play about the tense marriage of Maggie and the alcoholic Brick Pollitt written by Tennessee Williams.", "answer": "Cat on a Hot Tin Roof", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Cat on a Hot Tin Roof</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Cat on a Hot Tin Roof"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A group of girls in this work sing to kiss Gwennie or give her a penny. Theclock has been stopped for fifty years at a bar in this work called Sailors Arms, runby Sinbad. Mr Utah Watkins counts sheep at Salt Lake Farm, and another characteris told of his drunken antics by his wife, (+) Mrs Cherry Owen. Dai Bread has twowives and Mrs Ogmore-Pritchard nags her two former husbands. The central town is woken up by a sermon on (*) Coronation Street delivered by Reverend Eli Jenkins. This work features romances between Lily Smalls and Nogood Boyo and between the businessman Mog and Myfanwy Price. This work opens with the dreams of characters including Captain Cat and Organ Morgan. For ten points, identify this \"play for voices\" about the residents of Llaregub written by Dylan Thomas.", "answer": "Under Milk Wood", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Under Milk Wood</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Under Milk Wood"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poet wrote of \"country comets\" \"shining unto no higher end/ than topresage the grass's fall\" in The Mower to the Glowworms. This poet suggested thatApollo and Pan pursued Daphne and Syrinx for the plants they became in a workwhose first stanza notes that \"all flowers and all trees...weave the garlands of (+)repose\". In that work, he wrote that \"No white nor red was ever seen/ So amorous as this lovely green\" in praise of that \"happy (*) garden-state/ While man there walked without a mate\". He urged to \"tear/ Thorough the iron gates of life\" and to \"roll all our strength and all/ Our sweetness up into one ball\" in another poem. This poet of The Garden wrote that his \"vegetable love\" could grow \"Till the conversion of the Jews\" if only he had \"world enough and time\". For ten points, name this poet of To His Coy Mistress.", "answer": "Andrew Marvell", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Andrew <b><u>Marvell</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Andrew Marvell"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author wrote a short story in which the plain title character is pursuedby the handsome John Marble, causing her mother to anticipate the failure of theirmarriage. In addition to telling about the widow Mrs. Ewing in (+) Lolita, this writertold of a character who gave his wife a black eye and left her for two days when she joked about it while drinking. The protagonist of that story toasts drinks with her husband saying \"Here's mud in your eye!\". She spends nights at (*) Jimmy's with her boyfriends when that husband, Herbie, leaves her for Detroit. That title character travels to New Jersey to obtain two vials of veronal, but her attempt at suicide with them is unsuccessful. For ten points, name this author who created Hazel Morse in Big Blonde, a founding member of the Algonquin Round Table.", "answer": "Dorothy Parker", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Dorothy <b><u>Parker</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Dorothy Parker"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man referenced Carl Sandburg in a poem saying \"chicago? the hogbutcher!meatpacker! whatever! who cares? it's also like cleveland! like cincinnati!\" Anotherpoem by this man begins \"aretha/ crystal jukebox queen of hymn &amp; him\" anddeclares \"now's not the time to act silly, so wear your big boots &amp; jump on thegarbage clowns\". This man wrote of the title entity (+) \"Blowing like a circle aroundmy skull/ From the Grand Coulee Dam to the Capital\" in a work that repeats \"It's a wonder that you still know how to breathe\". This poet of the collection (*) Tarantula included Idiot Wind in his Blood on the Tracks. For ten points, identify this poet of who is also known for writing and playing songs such as Subterranean Homesick Blues and Mr. Tambourine Man, the 2016 Nobel Laureate in Literature.", "answer": "Bob Dylan (or Robert Allan Zimmerman)", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Bob Dylan</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Bob Dylan"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Robert Allan Zimmerman"}, {"question": "One character in this novel does not prepare anything for the Spring Exchangeand is told by his teacher that he does not need to be creative. Another character isthis novel cries after lying about the source of her pencil box. Three friends visit awashed-up (+) boat in a marsh, and earlier had traveled to Norfolk with Rodney andChrissie in search of a \"possible\" for Ruth since Norfolk is England's \"lost corner\". The narrator works on an essay about Victorian novels at (*) The Cottages, and earlier had made Madame cry by dancing with a pillow, her \"baby\", to a Judy Bridgewater song. Tommy completes after his fourth donation, and after leaving Hailsham, Kathy works as a carer. For ten points, name this novel about organ-donating clones by Kazuo Ishiguro.", "answer": "Never Let Me Go                                                                                                                                                                                                       ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Never Let Me Go</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Never Let Me Go"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel writes the story The Mountain Eyrie about a fiancethought to have died in World War I surviving in the hills. Another character uses theexamples of Florence Nightingale and Anna Pavlova to demonstrate that women don'tneed \"team spirit\". After being told to fight for (+) Franco, Joyce Emily Hammonddies in a train attack in Spain. This novel's protagonist was seen kissing the one-armed teacher in the art room; (*) Mr. Lloyd later paints Rose Stanley, who is \"famous for sex\", and sleeps with Sandy, who betrays the protagonist to Miss Mackay for her fascist sympathies. The protagonist insists that \"All my pupils are the cr`eme de la cr`eme\". For ten points, name this novel about a girls' school teacher and her \"set\" of six chosen proteges written by Muriel Spark.", "answer": "The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story by this author, the narrator thought her 4-year-old son had spilledpalm oil on himself when he was shot by soldiers, but can not recount the storywhen trying to obtain an asylum visa. In a novel by this author, the narrator's fatherresponds to his father's death by scalding his children's feet with water. This authorof the story (+) The American Embassy wrote of Ade Coker, the editor of TheStandard, dying from a mail bomb in the wake of a coup. The narrator of that novel is forbidden from visiting her grandfather because he is considered a pagan by her Catholic father. While visiting (*) Nsukka, where her aunt works as a university instructor, the narrator learns that her father died from poisoned tea. For ten points, name this author whose Purple Hibiscus is set in her native Nigeria.", "answer": "Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Chimamanda Ngozi <b><u>Adichie</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Three characters in this novel cut five legs off of a spider. The protagonist of thisnovel loses his pet, Groucho, to tetanus contracted from eating bailing wire, and wasarrested while questioning the opera singer (+) Luba Luft. The chickenhead J. R.Isidore endlessly watches the television show of Buster Friendly, which airs an expos \u0301e on the true identity of Wilbur Mercer. The Boneli Reflex-Arc Test measuring (*) neural speed is offered as an alternative to the empathy-based Voigt-Kampff Test, which Rachel Rosen failed. In this novel, set in the aftermath of World War Terminus, prices of animals are listed in Sidney's catalogs, and the protagonist buys a goat to celebrate retiring three andys in one day. For ten points, name this novel about the bounty hunter Rick Deckard written by Philip K. Dick.", "answer": "Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?                                                                                                                                                   ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character created by this playwright is wished \"cordolences\" after the deathof his grandfather and ends that play frantically hatching eggs. In a prequel, thatcharacter rejects a girl on account of her two noses, but ultimately agrees to marryRoberta. This playwright, who followed (+) Jack, or Obedience with The Future isin Eggs, created a character who impresses her teacher by naming all four seasons, but the teacher is upset that she can add and multiply but not subtract; that teacher ignores her toothache and (*) stabs her to death. In another play, a cat is trampled, the Logician is identified by his boater hat, Jean's skin turns green, and the protagonist is left by Daisy. For ten points, name this man who wrote The Lesson and of Berenger's refusal to transform in Rhinoceros.", "answer": "Eug`ene Ionesco (or Eugen Ionescu)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Eug`ene Ionesco</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Eug`ene Ionesco"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Eugen Ionescu"}], "bonuses": []}